<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nathan Cheever</title>
    <link>https://nathancheever.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nathan Cheever</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathancheever.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Questions to be lived</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/questions/</guid>
      <description>Not often, but sometimes, you stumble upon a question that is so profound to you that you would almost be sad to find the answer. It keeps you searching yourself, calling upon something deeper than rote learning or textbook memorization.
Perhaps we can call these “floating questions.” They evade scientific explanation.
Floating questions demand an answer from your life. They can generate enormous passion, send humans into space, and create beautiful art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a good day, 
Have a good life</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/goodday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/goodday/</guid>
      <description>One golden afternoon last October, while taking a walk, I wrote a thought down: &amp;ldquo;Eventually, my life will just be as good as my days. So I need to enjoy my days if I am going to enjoy my life.&amp;quot;
Embedded in there is the idea that no one state or achievement will likely &amp;ldquo;make&amp;rdquo; my life. Instead of some grandiose event, life&amp;rsquo;s quality is subject to more prosaic influences like the quality of our relationships, sleep, self-talk, hobbies, and food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please consider rebelling</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/rebel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/rebel/</guid>
      <description>There is a terrible temptation (I know I’ve fallen into many times) to value yourself by your productivity.
The meritocracy culture says monetary accumulation is the gateway to everything we desire: respect, independence, even happiness.
Hearing rhetoric like: “with the internet, not being a millionaire is a choice” for people like me who’ve accomplished very little according to the rules of the game, it can feel absolutely crushing.
Being ordinary is shamed as not hustling hard enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/top/about/</guid>
      <description>What is this blog? Everything I write here is written with the intent to learn and explore ideas I find interesting. Maybe you will too! Why do it?:
 Alzheimers runs in my family and I want to keep my mind alive and growing so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t die before I do. I&amp;rsquo;m tired of putting it off. I want to be a better writer and thinker. I want to be an influence for good and pay it forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/top/books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/top/books/</guid>
      <description>My Top Books How To Read a Book by Mortimer J. Adler and Charles Van Doren. The Second Mountain: The Quest for a Moral Life by David Brooks The Abolition of Man by C.S. Lewis </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moderation in moderation</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/moderation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/moderation/</guid>
      <description>There are special times in life to go all out.
Last year, I went all out on a 50-mile hike alone, completing it in 19 hours.
I learned some invaluable lessons like
 Don&amp;rsquo;t trust Google maps over mountains (I got lost) Always pack an extra almond poppyseed muffin. Stopping to rest only makes your legs hurt more.  More importantly, I learned that after being alone and exhausted for hours, all the noise in your head quiets down, and you come to know yourself and your limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plato, the moral revolutionary</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/plato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/plato/</guid>
      <description>Almost 2400 years ago, one of the greatest revolutions the western world has ever known set off.
It was a relatively quiet explosion, not a famous battle or the overthrow of an empire. It was a young man watching his hero, teacher, and mentor put on trial and condemned to death. His teacher had dedicated his life to questioning others, for, as he put it, &amp;ldquo;the unexamined life is not worth living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posts Archive</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/top/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/top/archive/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Talk as an Onramp</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/talk/</guid>
      <description>As an introvert, small talk has never come easy for me. I enjoy watching the occasional football or basketball game. Still, I can&amp;rsquo;t talk at length about the recent trades or injuries.
And the latest on TV or streaming shows? Nope, I&amp;rsquo;m lost. I don&amp;rsquo;t say this to boast, for if anything, it&amp;rsquo;s hindered me in quickly finding common ground in the break room.
Last year, I caught a ride home with a coworker who lived nearby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relationist</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/relationist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/relationist/</guid>
      <description>Last October I was walking to lunch with a friend. The Vice-Presidential debate happened the night before, and I glibly remarked about my hopes for the election outcome. Until that moment, I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that my friend felt differently.
After about 30 minutes of awkward but polite conversation, it was clear that we disagreed. I tried to mute my sarcasm, but it slipped out once when I said, &amp;ldquo;If Darth Vader pretended to support the policies you supported, would you still vote for him?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
