<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shorter on Nathan Cheever</title>
    <link>https://nathancheever.com/categories/shorter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shorter on Nathan Cheever</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nathancheever.com/categories/shorter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Questions to be lived</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/questions/</guid>
      <description>Not often, but sometimes, you stumble upon a question that is so profound to you that you would almost be sad to find the answer. It keeps you searching yourself, calling upon something deeper than rote learning or textbook memorization.
Perhaps we can call these “floating questions.” They evade scientific explanation.
Floating questions demand an answer from your life. They can generate enormous passion, send humans into space, and create beautiful art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a good day, 
Have a good life</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/goodday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/goodday/</guid>
      <description>One golden afternoon last October, while taking a walk, I wrote a thought down: &amp;ldquo;Eventually, my life will just be as good as my days. So I need to enjoy my days if I am going to enjoy my life.&amp;quot;
Embedded in there is the idea that no one state or achievement will likely &amp;ldquo;make&amp;rdquo; my life. Instead of some grandiose event, life&amp;rsquo;s quality is subject to more prosaic influences like the quality of our relationships, sleep, self-talk, hobbies, and food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Please consider rebelling</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/rebel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/rebel/</guid>
      <description>There is a terrible temptation (I know I’ve fallen into many times) to value yourself by your productivity.
The meritocracy culture says monetary accumulation is the gateway to everything we desire: respect, independence, even happiness.
Hearing rhetoric like: “with the internet, not being a millionaire is a choice” for people like me who’ve accomplished very little according to the rules of the game, it can feel absolutely crushing.
Being ordinary is shamed as not hustling hard enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moderation in moderation</title>
      <link>https://nathancheever.com/post/moderation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nathancheever.com/post/moderation/</guid>
      <description>There are special times in life to go all out.
Last year, I went all out on a 50-mile hike alone, completing it in 19 hours.
I learned some invaluable lessons like
 Don&amp;rsquo;t trust Google maps over mountains (I got lost) Always pack an extra almond poppyseed muffin. Stopping to rest only makes your legs hurt more.  More importantly, I learned that after being alone and exhausted for hours, all the noise in your head quiets down, and you come to know yourself and your limits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
